hey guys this looks like a fun one we
have 12 to power of x - 4 is equal to
the < TK of 2 to^ 2x - 4 if you want to
try this on your own pause it right now
cuz I'm going to solve it in 3 2 1 so
first let's copy down the exponents and
let's leave the parentheses blank we
want to express these two with the same
base 1/2 and S > of two both contain a
two so for both of them we're going to
do two to some power for this on the
left we're going to use a negative
exponent so if you have X to 1 that's
equal to 1 /x that takes the X on top
and puts it on bottom or if you have 1X
to the1 that takes the X on bottom and
puts it on top so regardless of which
one you start with it takes the
reciprocal to make it look like our
situation we can change these X's into
twos and now we have 2 the1 is equal to2
well that means that we can rewrite this
1/2 as 2 to the1 so we haven't changed
anything on the left hand side we've
only changed how we expressed it so now
on the right hand side side we're going
to use rational exponents it says x 1 /
n is equal to the N root of x well in
this particular example it's the square
root so we're going to do the square
root of x and the square root has an
implied index of two so that means this
n is going to be equal to two so the
square < TK of two is the same thing as
2 to the 1/2 power that means this
Square < TK of two is the same thing as
2 to the 1/2 power and now we can move
on to the next step we're doing the
power of a power these are the notes
right here if you have x to the a print
pareses to the B that's the same thing
as X the a * B so for the left hand side
2 -1 x - 4 is the same thing as 2-1 * x
- 4 and then if we distribute this 1 to
both terms this x - 4 becomes x + 4 and
then we're going to do the same thing on
the right hand side this 1/2 is going to
multiply by the 2x - 4 and that 1/2 will
cut both of these terms in half so 2x -
4 is going to change into 1 x - 2 so we
have 2 to this power is equal to 2 to
this power now that we've made the bases
match we can drop the base Drop the
Base and we can set the exponents equal
to each other and solve for x we have a
negative X and a positive X let's move
this x to this side we'll do that by
adding X to both sides and I want to
move this two to the other side so we'll
do that by adding two to both sides on
the left hand side these two x's will
cancel each other out leaving us with
six and on the right hand side these two
twos will cancel each other out leaving
us with X+ X or 2x after we divide both
sides by two we get 3 is equal to X and
that is the answer to our question xal 3
let's put a box around it how exciting